<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Origin on RebuildEQ</title>
    <link>/changelog/tags/origin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Origin on RebuildEQ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 01:19:18 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/changelog/tags/origin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Origin Binders added to Kunark and Velious</title>
      <link>/changelog/2016/06/07/origin-binders-added-to-kunark-and-velious</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 01:19:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/changelog/2016/06/07/origin-binders-added-to-kunark-and-velious</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overthere, Firiona Vie, Skyshrine, Kael, and Thurgadin are now rested EXP zones if your faction is &amp;gt; dubious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overthere, Firiona Vie, Skyshrine, Kael, and Thurgadin offer Origin Binding features near the banks if your faction &amp;gt; dubious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a new command, #exp. This is for 60+.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bard&amp;rsquo;s Jonathon&amp;rsquo;s Whistle had some typos in the build description (due to me copy pasting shaman description).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encounters now respect factions of the encounter triggerer, e.g. if in east commons and you&amp;rsquo;re not glare+ to freeport guards, they will not be an encounter to fight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low level zombies, mummies, etc (lvl 24 and lower) no longer cast disease due to how detrimental it is with the convenience commands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pets also gain #buff effects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#encounter now works as an alias for #encounters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#build now works as an alias for #builds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#experience now works as an alias for #exp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#rest now works as an alias for #rested&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skillup Rate Doubled</title>
      <link>/changelog/2016/06/06/skillup-rate-doubled</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 01:19:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/changelog/2016/06/06/skillup-rate-doubled</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skillup Rate changed from 100% to 200%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translocator Ionie at Nro docks now will assist players looking to adventure to Velious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shaman Cannibalization AA is no longer usable when the rank is reset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pets no longer persist after zoning if you no longer have the the build skill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pets have a minimum hp threshold, i need to test this more, be patient with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pets poof now when you #builds reset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed Named Spawns so they actually spawn if they had a fabled PH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goblin Card Added</title>
      <link>/changelog/2016/06/05/goblin-card-added</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 01:19:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/changelog/2016/06/05/goblin-card-added</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goblin Card is now a shrink clicky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orcs no longer will drop Goblin Cards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed Trakanon Idol requirement for Sebilis access. Later I&amp;rsquo;ll write an alternative quest to obtain key since I don&amp;rsquo;t require players to have a tracker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Shadowed Man Card. (Casts gather shadows). rarity is really rare, as a balancing aspect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shadowknight&amp;rsquo;s Siphon Death skill will also include Vampiric Embrace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>